Guide to the Charlie Steinmann Papers, 1937-1988 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Charlie Steinmann papers 1937-1988 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Steinmann, Charlie.
0.4 Linear Feet 280 Items
Charlie Steinmann was an executive in the outdoor advertising industry, primarily in the Pennsylvania region, working with Superior Sign Systems, Penn-York Advertising and Lamar Outdoor Advertising. He was inducted into the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA) Hall of Fame in 1995.
The Charlie Steinmann Papers span the years 1937-1988 and include printed materials, photographs, videocassettes, correspondence, financial reports and maps. Companies represented in the collection include Bishop-Holder Advertising, Lamar Outdoor Advertising, Penn Adams Advertising and Penn-York Advertising, all of which operated in the central Pennsylvania region. Collection also contains files on the Reserve Officer Association after World War II. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed to research until a use copy can be produced. Contact Research Services for further information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charlie Steinmann Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1954 Joined Superior Sign Systems
1966 Joined Penn-York Advertising
1973 Corporate Operations Manager, Penn-York Advertising
1991-1997 General Manager, Penn-York Advertising
1995 Inducted into Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA) Hall of Fame
1997-1999 Director, Northern Region Operations, Lamar Outdoor Advertising (Lamar acquired Penn-York in 1997)
1999 Safety Director, Lamar Outdoor Advertising
Charlie Steinmann has also served on the Board of Directors of the Better Business Bureau; as CEO of Lancaster Youth for Christ; and as a member of the International Association of Lions Clubs.
Collection Overview
The Charlie Steinmann Papers span the years 1937-1988 and include printed materials, photographs, videocassettes, correspondence, financial reports and maps. Companies represented in the collection include Bishop-Holder Advertising, Lamar Outdoor Advertising, Penn Adams Advertising and Penn-York Advertising, all of which operated in the central Pennsylvania region. Collection also contains files on the Reserve Officer Association after World War II.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is arranged into 4 series: General Files, Outdoor Advertising Companies, Printed Material, and Audiovisual Materials.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Steinmann, Charlie.
Penn Advertising, Inc
Advertising, Outdoor
Advertising, Outdoor -- History
Advertising, Outdoor -- Pennsylvania
Advertising, Outdoor -- Pennsylvania -- History
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States -- History
Billboards
Billboards -- Pennsylvania
Billboards -- Pennsylvania -- History
Billboards -- United States
Billboards -- United States -- History
Pennsylvania -- Commerce
Reserve Officers Association of the United States
Photographs
Videocassettes
Pennsylvania
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related material may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Burr L. Robbins Papers
Garrett Orr Papers
Howard Scott Papers
James O'Shaughnessy Papers
John Paver Papers
Robert A. Hamer Papers
Naegele Outdoor Records
Ohio Outdoor Advertising Corporation Records
Outdoor Advertising Association of America Archives
Contents of Collection
- General Files, 1937-1977 and undated
  - Charlie Steinmann biography, undated (Box 1)
  - Memoranda, 1942-1977
  - Photographs, 1937-1971
- Outdoor Advertising Companies, 1947-1988 and undated
  - Bishop-Holder Advertising, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Penn Adams Advertising, 1963
  - Penn-York Advertising
    - Balance sheets, 1950-1954, (4 folders)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1984-1988
    - Reserve Officers Association, 1947-1948
    - Shop photographs, 1960s-1972, (2 folders)
  - United Advertising Company, 1960s-1980s
- Printed Material 1947-1975
  - American National Standards Institute (ANSI), Building Code Requirements for Sign and Outdoor Display Structures, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Highway Research Board, Control of Highway Advertising Signs: Some Legal Problems, 1971
  - National Highway Users Conference (NHUC), Highway Highlights, 1948 Jan.
  - U.S. Department of Labor, Recordkeeping Requirements, 1971
  - U.S. Public Roads Administration, Public Control of Highway Access and Roadside Development, 1947
- Audiovisual Materials, undated
  [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
  - Penn Advertising--New Employee Orientation. Undated. Format: VHS. Undated. TRT: 30:00 (Box 2)